Lydia Ann St LIVERPOOL, L1 1QE +44 7870 597616 GEDKIRKHAM@PROTONMAIL.COM GITHUB.COM/GEDKIRKHAM GEDKIRKHAM.DEV

## **GED KIRKHAM**

A keen learner who is passionate about learning new skills and is constantly expanding their knowledge base through podcasts, articles and books. A fast learner who worked as a software tester for three years before stepping into the world of software development. Appreciates the benefits of a test driven, agile focused working environment.

#### **SKILLS**

- → Developed multiple Vue based web applications
- → Developed a React based SPA
- → Developed in Django back-end framework - Python
- → Created and edited SQL models
- → Developed GraphQL APIs
- → Develops with TDD mindset
- → Successful unit test integration with Docker CI/CD pipeline
- → Conducted E2E automation testing
- → Partaken in Agile development processes
- → Developed a C# console application
- → Aided in the maintenance of a Java test automation suite
- → Implemented a bash testing framework
- → Developed and executed test scripts for web and mobile applications

- → Developed proficient knowledge of XQuery to execute queries within a NoSQL database
- → Designed and maintained test metrics for stakeholders

#### Technology and tools:

Proficient in Javascript, Vue, Jest, HTML, CSS and Bash. Knowledgeable in React, Cypress, Java, Python, CI/CD processes, C#, XQuery and SQL. Good/basic understanding of Docker, C and C++.

Knowledgeable in VSCode, Eclipse, JIRA and Jenkins. Good/basic understanding of Azure builds

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Tuli Health, London - Full stack web developer

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

Worked as a full stack developer on two separate Vue based SPA web applications – Smartlingual and Tuli Health (<a href="https://portal.tuli.health">https://portal.tuli.health</a>). Was lead developer for Tuli Health where I managed the release cycles and CI/CD processes.

When developing the front-end, UX was carefully considered and reviewed by myself and the wider team. Performance is a critical component of web applications, so steps were taken to ensure that conditional components were dynamically loaded, images compressed, and API calls reduced to the minimum. Route guards were added to ensure certain areas of the website were hidden, and

data pre-fetch functions were implemented to ensure data was retrieved/manipulated before the component was rendered.

Django was used for the backend framework on both applications, and considerable time was spent working on the login, signup and password reset functionality. Models were designed and created, and API's developed which allowed the front-end to interact with the backend via GraphQL queries. When creating APIs, security checks were integrated to ensure that only authorised personnel could request relevant data.

#### TPICAP, London - Test consultant

JANUARY 2017- MAY 2019

Worked as part of a team to deliver regulatory requirements to a fixed deadline. Led end-to-end testing for two major regulatory components. Tutored colleagues on how to apply bash scripting to everyday testing, and developed a bash testing framework with an associated test matrix.

Conducted investigations to identify root causes of data issues which required a good understanding of the trading lifecycle, proficient XQuery skills to locate correct data, and efficiency at communicating results with key stakeholders.

Organised meetings with developers and business analysts to refine requirements. Ensured that key developers were aware of issues(s) and when required, assisted developers in replicating the issue.

#### ICSA Software, London - Test consultant

SEPTEMBER 2016 - DECEMBER 2016

Worked as part of a team that created and executed a test pack for both an iOS and web application. Key responsibilities included test pack design through detailed product evaluation, producing metric documentation, mobile testing, integration and exploratory testing. Worked alongside an internal testing team and offered advice on how to improve their test design process.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Huddersfield University** — BSc (Hons) Music Technology and Audio Systems; 1st Classification

SEPTEMBER 2012 - JUNE 2016

Coding languages such as C, C++, CSS3 and HTML5 were used to create websites, design digital audio filters and create software programs to control MIDI hardware and software. An understanding of audio technology hardware and software, and an understanding of basic filter design and implementation was gained through laboratory work.

#### **CERTIFICATES**

#### CISI Derivative Operations

The qualification gave a wide overview of the financial sector including the history, regulatory evolution, OTC and exchange products.